Hello.
Good afternoon, good evening,
depending on where you're hearing from.
I'm Faith Samuel Bassey.
[?] And I'm here to do my presentation
in collaboration with my super mentor.
And I want to share my slides.
Hope you don't mind.
I’m talking on “Reacting
to Electronic Literature
in Akwa Ibom State, Nigeria:
The Challenges, Possibilities,
and the Call for Accessibility.”
In my second slide here,
I have abstracted the key points.
Electronic literature
remains an emerging field in Nigeria,
and we have challenges
which range from technological,
educational, and institutional.
And we're going to reflect on
representing the Water Seller, “Mai Ruwa,”
and the focus on accessibility
and the audience engagement,
both for mobile-friendly and inclusive
electronic literature.
And in the next slide here,
we have the
introduction of digital literature.
This has transformed the way our stories
can be created,
distributed, and experienced.
Unlike a traditional print,
electronic literature
depends on digital technologies
for its production and reception,
and often, as we all know, incorporates
hyperlinks, multimedia elements,
interactive structures,
and non-linear narratives,
and invites readers to participate
actively.
Now we have
the current situation.
We have limited awareness.
The emergence of e-literature
in Nigeria presents both exciting
opportunities and significant challenges.
On one hand,
the widespread adoption of smartphones
and digital technologies
offers unprecedented possibilities
for digital innovation
and audience engagement.
On the other hand, inadequate
technologies
and limited scholarly expertise
and lack of institutional support hinder
the growth of electronic literature here
in Nigeria.
Now go to slide
four.
We have
limited awareness outside
specialized circles.
Few scholars and practitioners,
you know, we have limited people
who are trained in this field.
And the next slide is going to show
the opportunities in the Nigerian context,
the positive developments.
What we have here majorly: we have
people having access to smartphones,
and the growing
digital literacy, strong
social media engagement among the youth.
So what we have to do
is the expansion of mobile
literature,
just like the one I'm going to have
in my next slide.
This is a project in collaboration
with my mentor Deena,
the Water Seller, otherwise called “Mai
Ruwa.” It's one of the first digital-born
African literature works.
And from the next slide,
you see the woman with the baby
on her back and the water pot
she carries on the head.
We have all those notes there.
And we have the storyline: the water
she carries, the questions she asks,
the body she cherishes, the voice
she uses, the pain she knows, the strength
she understands, the love
she shares, and the future she hopes for.
This work can be read
through the mobile phone.
And it's also online, published
in the New River Journal,
and you can also find it on
Deena Larsen’s website.
And this work can be read
through the non-linear work
anyhow, just by clicking the notes.
And it has different interpretations.
The reader is also a creator of meaning.
The Water Seller challenges traditional
publishing models, enables global
readership, and demonstrates
possibilities
for African electronic literature.
We can find it on the website down below.
Now, I want to talk on my experience
in presenting electronic literature,
the Mai Ruwa, at
the University French Teachers’
Association of Nigeria, UFTAN,
at the Nnamdi Azikiwe University
last year.
It was a live demonstration
of electronic literature work.
That was what it was supposed to be.
But there was so much challenge.
We have technological
challenges, the problems
we encountered: projector malfunctioning,
no internet connection, inability
to demonstrate the work directly.
Now, the assumption
about the technological
infrastructure fails
in many academic environments.
We had audience reaction.
They were so excited.
They were enthusiastic to learn.
But there were also other concerns.
Now, the question that was raised
was that, you know,
in a traditional setting, in literature,
African and traditional literature,
when you want to do the analysis
of a particular text or novel,
so to say,
you must have a theory to back it up with.
So the question that was raised was:
what are the theories that we can use to
analyze electronic literature?
And—
So, I was able to tell them
that depending on the story
you have to tell, depending on the story
in your project, you can use
any kind of theory that suits it.
I brought out a personal theory
that they could use in that my work,
because my work talks about the woman
and the tradition that impeded her life,
and how she’s supposed to conquer
despite the tradition.
And to them,
the woman was supposed to go to school;
in the picture,
she was able to conquer this challenge.
That was also a major problem.
Then what we have
now is that the challenges are:
we have limited readership, because
back here, you find out
that people are not really funded;
minimal academic
attention; difficulty in measuring impact.
That’s a lot of invisibility.
So you realize that,
because of funding— I’ve heard
there is someone that’s supposed to be
presenting today, you have to go somewhere
to do a recording file
because of network challenges.
So that's the issue we have here.
So it was also of the opinion that
if we can do a call
to action, that we have more
teaching, more
training on the community
people for us over here.
And, being that the infrastructure
remains a challenge.
There was a piece on access today.
The question was, what can be done?
Is there a way this electronic literature
can be taught
in a challenging environment?
That’s always been my question.
I asked that question yesterday,
and I think someone answered me.
I think Miss Alina also answered.
He said that
he's going to work on that project.
So that's my challenge.
What can we do to help this?
That we are in a challenging environment?
That's my own point,
where I'm going to raise the case
and allow my mentor to talk.
Thank you.